# **Curriculum Vitae**

#### **Personal**

Name Kangogo Joel

Address 07, 30405 Tenges

Phone number +254722146545

Email kangogojoel25@gmail.com

Website https://jkangogo.github.io

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/kangogo-joel-a43655199

I am an innovative software engineer driven to solve complex challenges. I can merge deep technical proficiency with strategic leadership, allowing me to grow through continuous learning and improvement.

With experience in mobile, web, RFID/NFC/IoT programming, technical writing, R&D, and tech mentorship, I am driven to deliver solutions that push the boundaries of innovation.

# Work experience

Jan 2022 - Present

## **Software Engineer**

J-Class Solutions Inc,, Danbury CT

Developed and programmed RFID/NFC/BLE IoT devices for innovative home automation solutions and implemented AI algorithms for an LLM Autocomplete application.

Jan 2021 - Present

## **Vetted Software Engineer**

LD Talent, California

Spending 40+ hours/week crafting efficient web/mobile app code, designing intuitive UI/UX designs, and reviewing web blog content.

Aug 2023 - Apr 2024

#### Research Admin

GIZ, Kenya, Nairobi

Analyzed 50+ legal documents, conducted 15 interviews with stakeholders, and drafted an implementation plan adopted by GIZ and MoICDE.

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021

## Software Engineer Intern

3moderm Systems Ltd., Nairobi

As a software Engineer Intern, I reverse-engineered a web-based system into the mobile version of a rental management system, enhancing property management efficiency and thus providing amazing solutions to property owners to minimize their rental losses.

# **Education and Qualifications**

Sep 2016 - Mar 2022

#### **Bachelor of Science in Information Technology**

Kibabii University, Bungoma

Full-time student taking BSC. Information Technology

## Skills

Mobile app development (Java, Kotlin, Flutter)	••••
Web development (HTML, JavaScript, PHP, WP, Joomla	••••
Database (MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB)	
NFC/RFID/BLE Programming (Java-pi4J, Python)	••••
Data Science & Machine Learning (Python, R)	••••
Technical Writing (SEO tools, Markdown, Git, Jira)	••••
Research and Development	••••
IoT Systems Integration	• • • • •
Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)	

## Tasks & Achievements

# J-class Solutions Inc,

Senior level | Software Engineer Danbury, United States 2022-01-01 | Currently working here

Programming of RFID/NFC IOT Devices for Home Automation

Collaborated with J-Class Solutions' 5 engineers to develop innovative programs that utilize RFIDs/NFCs, IoT, and LLM
technologies for home automation and text prediction AI, achieving 95% user satisfaction, and enhancing life quality through
intuitive control.

#### **LD Talent**

Mid-level | Software Engineer California, United States 2021-01-01 | 2024-12-01

Evaluated and selected freelance software engineers with expertise in mobile and web application development, thereby enhancing project delivery timelines by ensuring top talent availability for critical tasks.

• My daily routine includes crafting efficient code for mobile applications, designing intuitive wireframes for mobile and web user interfaces, and producing engaging web content that captivates users.

### GIZ Kenya

Senior level | R&D Admin Nairobi, Kenya 2023-08-01 | 2024-04-01

Assumed the Role of R&D Assistant and delivered a comprehensive report for Software and Software Services:

- Analyzed over 50 legal documents within the sector to evaluate the efficacy, suitability, and structure in promoting agility, innovation, and value creation.
- Conducted 15 in-depth interviews with industry leaders to gather qualitative insights, enhancing the report's depth and relevance.
- Drafted a detailed implementation plan with 10 strategic actions for immediate execution, reducing time-to-innovation by 18 months.
- Successfully presented the reform report to GIZ and MoICDE, which was adopted by 90% of stakeholders for policy adjustments and sector support initiatives.

#### Prime Dimensions Ltd.

Senior level | Web Developer Nairobi, Kenya 2023-11-01 | 2024-01-01 Designed a Joomla website for Prime Dimensions Limited with custom HTML, CSS, and PHP:

- 99% device compatibility with responsive design.
- Easy CMS saving 10 hours/week on updates.
- 10,000+ words of content for engagement, up 75%.

See https://primedimensions.co.ke/

#### 3modern systems Ltd.

Internship & Graduate | Software Engineer Intern Nairobi, Kenya 2020-11-01 | 2021-04-01

Participated in the development of the mobile version of a rental management System for 3Modern Systems

• A management tool that keeps records of all your properties, tenants, payments, monetary usages, and generation of expenditure reports. With this management system, we provide an amazing solution to property owners to minimize their rental losses. https://github.com/jkangogo/3Modern-PropertyManager https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.threemodern.threepmanager

# **Certificates & Awards**

Fundamentals of Cybersecurity: Certificate | 2021

Data Science: Certificate | 2021 Machine Learning: Certificate | 2021

WordPress: Certificate | 2020

IT Industrial Training: Certificate | 2019

# References

The University of Nairobi Prof. Christopher Chepken

+254 722977672 chepken@gmail.com

MICDE Sectoral Working Group George Okado

+254 799751405

GeorgeWOkado@gmail.com

J-Class Solutions Inc,

**Thomas Garben** 

+1 914 874 7318 tom@j-class.com